{
  "title": "2.11",
  "definitions": {
    "INJURIOUS": {
      "word": "INJURIOUS",
      "phonetic": "(in-jUr'-E-ÔøΩs)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">causing injury, harmful </p><p>INJURIOUS is the adjective from INJURY, which means <i class=“def-ital\">harm</i>, <i class=“def-ital\">damage</i>, <i class=“def-ital\">wrongful action</i>. INJURIOUS means “causing, or tending to cause, an INJURY.” </p><p>“Smoking is INJURIOUS to your health.” </p><p>“He complained about the INJURIOUS treatments he had received from the phony doctor.” </p><p>In the Pretest, <i class=“def-ital\">wild</i> is a common choice as the meaning of INJURIOUS, probably because of confusion with the word <i class=“def-ital\">furious</i>. </p><p>Other forms of the word: INJURE,v., INJURY,n.</p>"
    },
    "MORSEL": {
      "word": "MORSEL",
      "phonetic": "(mor'-sÔøΩI)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a bit, small piece, scrap </p><p>MORSEL comes from a Latin word meaning to <i class=“def-ital\">bite</i>. A MORSEL is a small piece of food that could be eaten in one bite. </p><p>“You must eat every MORSEL on your plate before you get dessert.” </p><p>“He ate the last MORSEL of bread, and then there was nothing left.” </p><p>MORSEL can also be used about a small piece of news, knowledge, or the like. </p><p>“They picked up a few MORSELS of information about their ancestors there, but nothing very interesting.”</p>"
    },
    "PILLAR": {
      "word": "PILLAR",
      "phonetic": "(pil'-ÔøΩr)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a column, post </p><p>A PILLAR is a firm upright post which supports a ceiling or a building. </p><p>“Using all his strength Samson broke the PILLARS, and the building collapsed on top of him.” </p><p>PILLAR is also used generally about a person or thing that provides strong support. </p><p>“He was a PILLAR of the community. Without him this wouldn’t be such a good a place to live.”</p>"
    },
    "EXTERIOR": {
      "word": "EXTERIOR",
      "phonetic": "(eks-tEr'-EÔøΩr)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">outside, outer, external </p><p> EXTERIOR means <i class=“def-ital\">outer</i>, <i class=“def-ital\">outside</i>. </p><p>“They painted the EXTERIOR walls of the house and left the inside walls alone.” </p><p>“The EXTERIOR appearance of the building had faded over the years from the wind and the rain.” </p><p>EXTERIOR can also be used as a noun. </p><p>“He had a rugged EXTERIOR\"—that is, his outside appearance was strong and rough looking. The opposite of EXTERIOR is interior, which means <i class=“def-ital\">inner</i>, <i class=“def-ital\">inside</i>.</p>",
      "prefix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">ex-</i> under Prefixes."
      ]
    },
    "PREPOSTEROUS": {
      "word": "PREPOSTEROUS",
      "phonetic": "(pri-pos'-tÔøΩr-ÔøΩs)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">absurd, completely foolish, totally unreasonable </p><p>Anything PREPOSTEROUS is absolutely absurd, completely without sense or reason. It comes from a Latin word meaning “having the back end in front.”  </p><p>“His ideas about the use of chewing gum to repair tires was PREPOSTEROUS.” </p><p>“She has the PREPOSTEROUS notion that telephone poles grow right where they are.” </p><p>“The book is PREPOSTEROUS. Nobody acts the way the author says they do.”</p>",
      "suffix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">pre-</i> under Prefixes and <i class=“def-ital\">-ous</i> under Suffixes."
      ]
    },
    "INSPIRE": {
      "word": "INSPIRE",
      "phonetic": "(in-splr')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to influence, arouse, uplift, exalt, encourage </p><p> The <i class=“def-ital\">spire</i> part of the word comes from the Latin word for breathe, which is also the source for words like <i class=“def-ital\">expire</i>, <i class=“def-ital\">perspire</i>, and <i class=“def-ital\">conspire</i>. To INSPIRE people is to breathe life, purpose, excitement, or some other feeling into them, to uplift or encourage them. </p><p>“The coach’s speech at halftime INSPIRED the team to try even harder.” </p><p>“The teacher INSPIRED in Jane a desire to learn more about the subject.” </p><p>“We were all INSPIRED by your wonderful example.” </p><p>“The foreman’s harsh words INSPIRED a great deal of anger among the workers.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: INSPIRATION,n.</p>",
      "prefix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">in-</i> under Prefixes."
      ]
    },
    "PROGRESS": {
      "word": "PROGRESS",
      "phonetic": "(prog'-res)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">advance, forward movement </p><p>PROGRESS is forward movement toward a goal. It is advancement or improvement.  </p><p>“We made some PROGRESS through the snowstorm, but finally we became stuck.” </p><p>“There was little PROGRESS in their efforts to end the war.” </p><p>“Scientists have made PROGRESS, but they still cannot cure the disease.” </p><p>The phrase “in PROGRESS” means “in the act of going forward,” still happening. </p><p>“He turned on the television show while it was in PROGRESS.” </p><p>PROGRESS is also a verb. </p><p>“He PROGRESSED rapidly for a while, but then seemed to get worse.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: PROGRESSION, n., PROGRESSIVE, adj.</p>",
      "prefix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">pro-</i> under Prefixes."
      ]
    },
    "CONSULT": {
      "word": "CONSULT",
      "phonetic": "(kÔøΩn-suhlt')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to confer, seek the advice of, refer to </p><p>To CONSULT something is to go to it for information, to refer to it. </p><p>“He CONSULTED the dictionary for the correct spelling of the word.” </p><p>“Did you CONSULT the phone book before you dialed the number?” </p><p>You can also CONSULT a person. </p><p>“The teacher CONSULTED the principal before taking her class to the museum.” </p><p>To CONSULT <i class=“def-ital\">with</i> someone is to confer with him, to talk over a problem and get advice. </p><p>“She CONSULTED with three lawyers about the complicated case.” </p><p>“I want to CONSULT with another doctor before deciding about the operation.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: CONSULTANT, n., CONSULTATION, n.</p>"
    },
    "DAWDLE": {
      "word": "DAWDLE",
      "phonetic": "(do'-dÔøΩI)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to waste time, delay </p><p>To DAWDLE is to spend too much time doing something. </p><p>“He would DAWDLE over his homework and never get it done.” </p><p>“If she liked what she was doing, she would rush right through it. If she didn’t, she would DAWDLE and waste time and finally leave it half finished.” </p><p>“Come straight home from school and don’t DAWDLE along the way!” </p><p><i class=“def-ital\">Talk stupidly</i> is often picked as the synonym for DAWDLE. This is probably due to confusion with <i class=“def-ital\">twaddle</i>, which is a noun meaning “foolish, silly talk.”</p>"
    },
    "SUPERVISE": {
      "word": "SUPERVISE",
      "phonetic": "(sU'-pÔøΩr-vlz)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to oversee, superintend, direct </p><p> To SUPERVISE is to oversee work or workers, to look over them, so that you can make sure things are done right. </p><p>“I have to SUPERVISE every step of the job to make sure no mistakes are made.” </p><p>“The general himself SUPERVISED the landing of the soldiers.” </p><p>Someone who SUPERVISES is a SUPERVISOR. The act of SUPERVISING is SUPERVISION. </p><p>“He thought that SUPERVISION wasn’t really necessary. The workers could do the job by themselves.” </p><p>The most common mistake is to choose <i class=“def-ital\">help</i> as the meaning of SUPERVISE. To SUPERVISE people is to direct them, to give them orders, not to help them. </p><p>Other forms of the word: SUPERVISION, n., SUPERVISOR, n., SUPERVISORY, adj.</p>",
      "prefix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">super-</i> under Prefixes."
      ]
    },
    "UNDERGO": {
      "word": "UNDERGO",
      "phonetic": "(uhn-dÔøΩr-gO')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to experience, suffer </p><p>UNDERGO means to <i class=“def-ital\">experience</i>, usually to experience something unpleasant. </p><p>“We had to UNDERGO several tests before we were through.” </p><p>“My father will UNDERGO an operation for his heart murmur.” </p><p>“The witness UNDERWENT several hours of questioning at the trial yesterday.” </p><p>Usage: The past tense of UNDERGO is UNDERWENT.</p>"
    },
    "DEPRESS": {
      "word": "DEPRESS",
      "phonetic": "(di-pres')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to discourage, sadden; to lower, press down </p><p> To DEPRESS basically means to <i class=“def-ital\">press down</i>. </p><p>“When a car’s accelerator is DEPRESSED, the car goes faster.” </p><p>DEPRESS is most often used in the sense “to press down on your spirits,” to discourage. </p><p>“The news of his death DEPRESSED all of us.” </p><p>“Joan was DEPRESSED by her failure to pass the course.” </p><p>“He has looked so DEPRESSED lately. Let’s try to cheer him up.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: DEPRESSING, adj. DEPRESSION, n.</p>",
      "prefix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">de-</i> under Prefixes."
      ]
    },
    "HUMANE": {
      "word": "HUMANE",
      "phonetic": "(hyU-mAn')",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">kind, compassionate, tender, benevolent </p><p>HUMANE, with an <i class=“def-ital\">e</i>, was once just another way of spelling <i class=“def-ital\">human</i>. The word has come to be used, however, only about the kindest or gentlest qualities of human beings. To be HUMANE is to be full of sympathy and consideration for other people or for animals. </p><p>“They were noted for their HUMANE treatment of the poor. No one was allowed to go hungry or homeless.” </p><p>“He was a HUMANE boss. He gave his workers time off if they really needed it.”</p>"
    },
    "FEE": {
      "word": "FEE",
      "phonetic": "(fE)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a charge, payment </p><p>A FEE is a charge for services. It is usually for professional services, like those of a doctor or a lawyer. </p><p>“The lawyer’s FEE was so high that we wondered if it had been worthwhile going to court.” </p><p>The word can also be used about any charge made for a right or privilege. </p><p>“The club raised its membership FEE by five dollars.” </p><p>“There is a small FEE for the use of the tennis courts.”</p>"
    },
    "INHABIT": {
      "word": "INHABIT",
      "phonetic": "(in-hab'-it)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to live in, dwell in </p><p> To INHABIT a place is to live in it. </p><p>“Several million people INHABIT that city.” </p><p>“A family of raccoons INHABITS the woods behind our house.” </p><p>An INHABITANT is someone who INHABITS a place, a resident. </p><p>“The firemen rescued all the INHABITANTS of the building.” </p><p>Many people choose <i class=“def-ital\">get used to</i> as the meaning of INHABIT, probably because they are confused by the word <i class=“def-ital\">habit</i>. </p><p>Other forms of the word: INHABITANT, n.</p>",
      "prefix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">in-1</i> under Prefixes."
      ]
    }
  },
  "id": "11",
  "exercises": [
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Threw a MORSEL.",
          "answers": [
            "few",
            "bit",
            "number",
            "lot",
            "bundle"
          ],
          "word": "MORSEL",
          "correct": "bit"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Strong PILLARS.",
          "answers": [
            "walls",
            "foundations",
            "bell towers",
            "columns",
            "door frames"
          ],
          "word": "PILLAR",
          "correct": "columns"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The EXTERIOR part.",
          "answers": [
            "inner",
            "worst",
            "rear",
            "first",
            "outside"
          ],
          "word": "EXTERIOR",
          "correct": "outside"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PREPOSTEROUS remarks.",
          "answers": [
            "useless",
            "unkind",
            "absurd",
            "pleasant",
            "serious"
          ],
          "word": "PREPOSTEROUS",
          "correct": "absurd"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They INSPIRED him.",
          "answers": [
            "influenced",
            "amused",
            "discouraged",
            "concerned",
            "interested"
          ],
          "word": "INSPIRE",
          "correct": "influenced"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SUPERVISE them.",
          "answers": [
            "speak to",
            "obey",
            "hire",
            "help",
            "oversee"
          ],
          "word": "SUPERVISE",
          "correct": "oversee"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "What will they UNDERGO?",
          "answers": [
            "lose",
            "see",
            "dig",
            "deserve",
            "experience"
          ],
          "word": "UNDERGO",
          "correct": "experience"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Their remarks DEPRESS me.",
          "answers": [
            "confuse",
            "discourage",
            "anger",
            "calm",
            "influence"
          ],
          "word": "DEPRESS",
          "correct": "discourage"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Rapid PROGRESS.",
          "answers": [
            "change",
            "retreat",
            "advance",
            "decision",
            "profit"
          ],
          "word": "PROGRESS",
          "correct": "advance"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CONSULT with him.",
          "answers": [
            "joke",
            "confer",
            "work",
            "argue",
            "visit"
          ],
          "word": "CONSULT",
          "correct": "confer"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Known to DAWDLE.",
          "answers": [
            "give up",
            "wonder",
            "work hard",
            "talk stupidly",
            "waste time"
          ],
          "word": "DAWDLE",
          "correct": "waste time"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "HUMANE people",
          "answers": [
            "pretty",
            "kindhearted",
            "popular",
            "crazy",
            "angry"
          ],
          "word": "HUMANE",
          "correct": "kindhearted"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Low FEE.",
          "answers": [
            "charge",
            "value",
            "spot",
            "tide",
            "note"
          ],
          "word": "FEE",
          "correct": "charge"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INHABIT the castle.",
          "answers": [
            "enter",
            "get used to",
            "discover",
            "live in",
            "attack"
          ],
          "word": "INHABIT",
          "correct": "live in"
        }
      ],
      "type": "mc-one",
      "id": "pretest"
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Should children play with INJURIOUS toys?",
          "word": "INJURIOUS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a few MORSELS make a good meal?",
          "word": "MORSEL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is it usually easy to break a PILLAR?",
          "word": "PILLAR",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does a can have an EXTERIOR?",
          "word": "EXTERIOR",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would it be PREPOSTEROUS to pay someone a million dollars to clean your home?",
          "word": "PREPOSTEROUS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can an object INSPIRE a person?",
          "word": "INSPIRE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do students usually SUPERVISE teachers?",
          "word": " SUPERVISE ",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do college students usually UNDERGO four years of schooling before they receive their degrees?",
          "word": " UNDERGO ",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a person usually be DEPRESSED if he had just lost his job?",
          "word": " DEPRESSED",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a person who walks very slowly make PROGRESS?",
          "word": " PROGRESS ",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do you CONSULT a problem to get the answer?",
          "word": " CONSULT ",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do people who DAWDLE always get where they are going on time?",
          "word": "DAWDLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is everybody HUMANE?",
          "word": "HUMANE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is there a FEE for free services?",
          "word": "FEE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can animals be INHABITANTS?",
          "word": "INHABITANTS",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ],
      "type": "tf",
      "id": 1
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Jack was INJURIOUS with us when he found out what we had done.",
          "word": "INJURIOUS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He bought a huge MORSEL of wood, enough to last the winter.",
          "word": "MORSEL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Several wooden PILLARS held up the balcony.",
          "word": "PILLAR",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The team is so far EXTERIOR to ours that we'll never beat them.",
          "word": "EXTERIOR",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "That was the largest bug I've ever seen. It was PREPOSTEROUS.",
          "word": "PREPOSTEROUS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The artist must have been INSPIRED when he painted that picture.",
          "word": "INSPIRE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Bill's father kept him under close SUPERVISION while he used the chainsaw.",
          "word": "SUPERVISION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The engineers decided to put in a tunnel so travelers could UNDERGO the mountain.",
          "word": "UNDERGO",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "I tried to DEPRESS what I thought, hut no one would listen to me.",
          "word": "DEPRESS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "His study of the language had PROGRESSED to the point where he could read it easily.",
          "word": "PROGRESSED",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "I shall have to CONSULT with your father before I can make a decision.",
          "word": "CONSULT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He thought it was funny to frighten the boy by DAWDLING him over the side of the boat.",
          "word": "DAWDLING",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They were very HUMANE in caring for stray cats and dogs.",
          "word": "HUMANE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The doctor's FEE was much more than we expected.",
          "word": "FEE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We INHABIT a small shack at the edge of town.",
          "word": "INHABIT",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ],
      "type": "tf",
      "id": 2
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "INJURIOUS",
          "answers": [
            "hurting",
            "harmful",
            "twisting"
          ],
          "word": "INJURIOUS",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MORSEL",
          "answers": [
            "piece",
            "end",
            "crumb"
          ],
          "word": "MORSEL",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PILLAR",
          "answers": [
            "strength",
            "softness",
            "upright"
          ],
          "word": "PILLAR",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "EXTERIOR",
          "answers": [
            "appearance",
            "outside",
            "middle"
          ],
          "word": "EXTERIOR",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PREPOSTEROUS",
          "answers": [
            "silly",
            "senseless",
            "noisy"
          ],
          "word": "PREPOSTEROUS",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INSPIRE",
          "answers": [
            "worry",
            "uplift",
            "excite"
          ],
          "word": "INSPIRE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SUPERVISE",
          "answers": [
            "parent",
            "boss",
            "baby"
          ],
          "word": "SUPERVISE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "UNDERGO",
          "answers": [
            "experience",
            "suffer",
            "worry"
          ],
          "word": "UNDERGO",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DEPRESS",
          "answers": [
            "make thoughtful",
            "sadden",
            "lower"
          ],
          "word": "DEPRESS",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PROGRESS",
          "answers": [
            "ahead",
            "forward",
            "always"
          ],
          "word": " PROGRESS ",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CONSULT",
          "answers": [
            "advise",
            "inform",
            "approve"
          ],
          "word": "CONSULT",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DAWDLE",
          "answers": [
            "giggle",
            "idle",
            "delay"
          ],
          "word": "DAWDLE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "HUMANE",
          "answers": [
            "tender¬∑",
            "gentle",
            "normal"
          ],
          "word": "HUMANE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FEE",
          "answers": [
            "money",
            "payment",
            "loan"
          ],
          "word": "FEE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INHABIT",
          "answers": [
            "reside",
            "visit",
            "live"
          ],
          "word": "INHABIT",
          "correct": "1"
        }
      ],
      "type": "mc-all",
      "id": 3
    }
  ]
}